ADAPTED FROM THE BLOSSOMING LOVE
BY SUI YU ER AN ON ICEREAD.COM
There is such a long secret tunnel
hidden under my mother's room.
I can't believe that
my father never told me about it.
It seems that Gao Fengxu,
has been hiding a lot of secrets
to you, his daughter.
This stone bed is covered
by Spirit Gathering Arrays.
The only thing that does
is to absorb the aura of nature
for cultivators to use.
So,
my father locked my mother up in here
to nourish the Chaos Pearl.
I think
the truth might be even crueler.
What truth?
I'm a tuco-tuco.
A kid.
Just a filthy spirit slave
without a spirit lock.
Take her away. Madam's task comes first.
Prepare the sword array
and destroy this place.
There is no window.
The sunshine
and noises
from the outside world can't get in.
There is no trace
of anyone ever living here.
Just a stone bed covered
by Spirit Gathering Arrays.
The size
doesn't even allow any movement.
So…
So, this place is not
for holding a living person.
It's for keeping a dead body.
Miss Gao…
I'm fine. Go on.
The body of a Primal Celestial Maiden
contains endless vitality.
No one knows if that will disperse
as she dies.
Your father visited this place often
after your mother passed away.
I think
he was using your mother's body
to keep nourishing the Chaos Pearl.
The Spirit Gathering Array
is to keep the vitality inside her
from stopping generating.
Mother!
Miss Gao…
Let me go! Leave me! Let me go!
Don't kill me.
-Go!
-Please!
-Come here.
Don't kill me. Please.
Please!
Father!
Father, is it you who saved me?
Father! Where are you?
Come out so that I can see you.
Father!
I want to see you.
-Father!
-Bao!
Do you not want Mother and I anymore?
Father!
Mr. Gao was once the leader
of the Immortal Alliance.
Would he commit something like that?
When Miss Gao said
that Saint Miaohua was held captive
and tortured by Madam Su for years,
I thought that was weird.
If Saint Miaohua just asked
Su Ningxi to marry Mr. Gao
and forced her to nourish the Chaos Pearl,
why would Madam Su hate her so much?
I'm going to my mother's tomb.
Master said that my mother
was buried with my father.
I will see for myself if she is there.
If Mirage Palace
still has the Chaos Pearl,
-then--
-No matter what,
the truth shouldn't be buried.
Whoever did all evil things
for the Chaos Pearl
should face the consequences.
The array is about to be ready.
Where is he?
-Let's forget about him.
-Yes.
We need to hurry up
and destroy this place.
What's going on?
Let's go. This place is going down.
Come on.
Watch out!
Are you staying at your crime scene
so that the victims can get their revenge?
You are not getting out of here alive.
I don't have time to waste on you.
You are not controlled by Heartstring.
It's too hard to kill you.
I wanted to take the chance to get away,
and these two
annoying people got in my way.
Why did you travel with me
in the first place?
To get the Chaos Pearl.
I've been telling you the truth.
The Chaos Pearl is still missing.
Why not keep lying to me?
I got the clue I wanted.
My master can take over from here.
As for you, maybe just die here.
However,
you still can't kill me, can you?
Mu Xuanling. Were you trying to kill me?
What's going on?
Where is Bao? Bao!
Bao!
Lansheng. Qiumin.
Why is your face bleeding?
Are you hurt?
That's not my blood.
The cultivators from Mirage Palace
tried to kill me.
My father saved me.
Your father. Did you see him?
He won't come out and meet with me.
He got away again.
It seems that this little girl's father
is no common man.
Xuanling.
Xuanling, why are you tied up?
She's a bad person. She should be tied up.
But Xuanling is not a bad person.
Xuanling. You are not a bad person, right?
Yes. Bao.
I'm not a bad person.
Will you help me?
Miss Mu.
Whatever you want,
don't trick and use a child.
The cultivators
from Mirage Palace are dead.
They can't report to duty.
Madam Su will get suspicious soon.
There's no time to waste.
Let's go to the graveyard first.
What about her?
I'll keep her close.
There's nobody in the coffin, as expected.
It's getting late.
Let's find a staging post
-and rest for the night.
-Mr. Xie
may have underestimated
the power of your Jade Vault Technique.
I have got a lot of new information today.
I'm going to report to duty.
-Xuanling!
-See? She's a bad person.
Move aside.
I will never let you
get back to Sang Qi again.
Mu Xuanling.
You have other choices.
Xie Xuechen.
Stop lying to yourself.
I am the same as my master.
You and I are not the same kind of people.
You love humanity and the world.
I am a member of the Spirit Clan.
This world
has never treated me with kindness.
And I
have never loved this world or you.
I've been lying to you
from the beginning.
I've seen your true heart.
Don't do anything that you will regret.
Are you really that unwilling
to let me go?
How about this?
Come back to the Dark Abyss with me.
Use your intelligence and power
to eliminate Sang Qi
and become the new Lord of the Dark Abyss.
That should be easy for you.
In that case,
you've gotten rid of Sang Qi for good,
and we will be on the same path.
What do you think, Mr. Xie?
You shouldn't go back to that life.
How stubborn.
You are not getting away. Give up.
What do you care?
Stay away!
Xuanling!
You are bleeding.
Bao!
Mr. Xie.
The blood… Is that yours?
Only the blood of a direct relative
can activate a blood mirror.
It's Miss Mu's blood on the mirror,
yet Miss Gao can see.
You two are direct relatives.
You are sisters.
How is that possible?
Who are you calling her sister?
So, Miss Mu.
-Are you still leaving?
-What do you think?
Before we get to the bottom of this,
no one is leaving.
You first.
It's not like I'm intimidated.
I don't believe
in something so ridiculous.
I'm not afraid.
See?
How…
How did that happen?
It's… It's impossible.
This is absurd. It can't be true.
I am a member of the Spirit Clan
while she's a human.
How can we be direct relatives?
Maybe you have
the same mother and different fathers.
Don't knock it!
If my mother gave birth to two children,
how could I not know?
How could no one know?
The only explanation is that,
Fu Lansheng,
your blood mirror is not working.
That must be it!
You can say what you want about me,
but our artifacts always work.
Studying artifacts is the livelihood
of Jade Sky Palace for a thousand years.
How could we make mistakes?
Let me show you!
LOVESTORY AT AN EMBROIDERY ROOM
What's that?
-It's not for a kid to see.
-What are you doing?
What? I didn't even see it clearly.
What is that?
What is it?
Let me go!
What is that?
-What's that?
-Sorry. I want to ask you guys
to keep this a secret among us.
Save my father some dignity.
Judging from the situation,
we'll have to ask
Madam Su about all this
at the Mirage Palace.
BRIGHT MOON INN
DECAYING IMMORTAL PAVILION
They've been to the tomb
in Moonlight Heights.
Su Ningxi's coffin
was empty.
They are traveling to Mirage Palace next.
Xie Xuechen might be smart,
but he's unlikely to think
that you'd come to my place
after leaving the Two Realms Mountain.
Isn't this your idea?
I usually get my medicine
on the first day of each month.
This month, there's still no news
about the medicine on the eighth.
You were forcing me to come here.
All people say that Mr. Nan
is a warm and gentle man.
How come you are always so mean
when talking to me?
I have saved your life, at least to say.
Back then, your sibling born
by your stepmother set you up,
and a demonic cultivator kept you captive
and tortured you.
I was the one
who saved you at the critical moment.
Sometimes I'd rather you didn't
when I think about that.
But you chose to live
on your own.
I didn't force you.
In the 10,000 years of this world,
there were only two people
born with ten spiritual channels.
Xie Xuechen is having a good life.
But how come you are
in this bad situation?
You've lost nine out of ten
of your vitality.
That one point is close to nothing.
I'll give you a choice.
Take your life
with this sword if you want to give up.
Or if you want to live,
take the medicine.
There is one thing bad about the medicine.
Once you take it,
you will have to take it every month.
That's how you can stay alive.
If you stop taking the medicine,
you will be dead
with double the pain
within a year.
If it's revenge that you want,
I can help you with that if you are dead.
Have you thought this through?
The Spirit Clan.
The Spirit Clan slaughtered this place.
You knew, didn't you?
Do you still hate Xingye and me?
So,
you let the Spirit Clan slaughter us.
Xue and my brother hate me.
They colluded with someone
and destroyed my spiritual channels.
You led your disciples
to suppress the Spirit Clan.
That's why they retaliated
and brought massacre to this place.
This is my fate.
And yours as well.
It is the fate of Greenview Heights.
Father,
you are going to ruin a master
for a dead kid.
Right?
You didn't let me down.
From now on,
you are the master of Greenview Heights.
You had your revenge
and met with the person you want to meet.
Mr. Nan,
where is the Chaos Pearl
that we agreed on?
I promised you
three wishes to pay back your help.
Your first request
was to set up a killing array
in Greenview Heights
and stall Xie Xuechen
on his way back to the city.
The second was to break
the double-sided barrier in Snow City
and let Ignorance Demon into the city.
The third was to leave a backdoor
on the All-Seeing Jade Dragon Array
so that the Spirit Clan
can still get into the city.
I have done all three things.
You didn't get the Chaos Pearl.
It is your problem.
I have no part in that.
You are helping
the Decaying Immortal Pavilion
while assisting Xie Xuechen
to fight the Decaying Immortal Pavilion.
You are putting me in a hard position.
That is also your problem.
I don't work for you,
so I don't have to follow your order.
As for your threat
of stopping the medicine,
to be honest, whether you are
giving it to me or not
makes no difference to me.
Mr. Nan is a world-famous hero.
How dare I threaten you?
There's one thing that I don't understand.
Mr. Nan has been waiting for so long
to reunite with your old friend.
Are you really letting her go?
Don't you want to take her for your own?
Do you need me
to kill Xie Xuechen?
That's my personal business.
You are no part of this.
I told you
that I wouldn't ask questions about
your collaboration with the Dark Abyss.
You
cannot meddle with my affair.
Mr. Nan, don't be mad.
I understand what you said.
I will not bother you
with what's happening next.
I will get you the medicine
every month on time
for the sake
of our cooperation.
There is one thing that I'm curious about.
More than ten years have passed,
and you haven't aged a day.
You also have
millennium-long treasures, such as
the Phoenix Herb and Illusion Elixir.
Forgive me for intruding,
but how old are you?
I stopped
counting my age
a long time ago.
There's no point.
Living for too long
is not necessarily a good thing.
The price
is way too painful.
Too painful.
Madam,
we've enquired
across the Immortal Alliance.
We don't have news on Qiumin yet.
You know how important she is.
Even if you have to travel
to the Dark Abyss
or sacrifice thousands of people,
do get her back!
Yes.
Ningxi,
I don't have many days left.
If we meet in the afterworld,
will you blame me?
-Here's your money.
-The world is disgusting.
If you knew that they would
become food when they grow up,
why bring them into the world?
Nice.
Ningzhen, run!
Ningxi!
Ningxi, I'm tired.
I can't keep running.
Rest here.
I'll go get you food.
Here.
How did you manage to do that?
I'm not sure.
I just felt its vitality
-and gave it a shot.
-That's wonderful!
We will never have to starve again.
They didn't know what you could do
and tried to eat us.
How stupid!
If someone learns about this,
I will die even more horribly.
I know.
Madam, this is the forest.
There is a location
where the aura is extremely thick.
There could be some talented people here.
Ningxi, I'm scared.
You… What do you want?
The body of a Primal Celestial Maiden.
The legend is real.
There are deities
who reincarnate in this world.
Good kid.
How old are you?
What's your name?
I'm Xi. I'm eight years old.
Xi.
I'm the Madam of Mirage Palace.
Will you come back
to Mirage Palace with me?
I will accept you as my disciple
and teach you cultivation and spells.
You don't have to worry about surviving.
You may even achieve immortality
and go to any corner
of the world as you wish.
I want to be with my sister, Zhen.
Ningxi, I'm scared.
I will protect you forever.
We will never be apart.
I failed to protect Qiumin.
After you left,
I haven't been able to do anything right.
Come with me to the Dark Abyss
and search for our young madam.
Elder, are we really traveling
to the Dark Abyss?
That's Sang Qi's territory.
Elder, it's the young madam. She's back.
Young Madam.
Madam, Qiumin is back.
Master.
What happened to your hair?
It's okay.
Mr. Xie.
You are back from the Dark Abyss.
Thanks to your prayer,
I will live for a little bit longer.
Mr. Xie, what important business
brought you here?
Things have changed in the Dark Abyss.
This might have something to do
with Sang Qi.
Madam Su, may I ask you
to clear the room?
Madam Su,
how many children has Su Ningxi
given birth to?
What is that supposed to mean?
The whole world knows
that my sister was married to Gao Fengxu
and gave birth to a girl.
She left this world right after that.
I mean no offense.
I got an artifact from Fu Lansheng,
and a test says that Miss Gao
is related to Mu Xuanling.
Mr. Xie, how ridiculous.
Are you saying
that they are sisters?
My sister has only one child,
and that is Qiumin.
Were you there
when she was in labor?
Of course.
When Qiumin was born,
there were unworldly views.
The room was so full of light
that it was too bright to see.
Too bright to see.
So, you didn't actually see.
Mr. Xie,
are you trying to smudge my sister's name?
My sister did have a history with Sang Qi,
but they couldn't have had a child.
Back then, my sister was…
Master, calm down first.
We just want to know the truth.
We are not trying
to ruin my mother's reputation.
Madam Su, forgive me
for being presumptuous.
Gao Qiumin's talent
is not worthy of an unworldly view.
Mr. Xie and Mr. Nan
were born with ten spiritual channels,
but they didn't have
any unworldly view when they were born.
Can't you talk politely?
Madam Su,
it's easy to verify their relationship.
If you don't trust our artifact,
use Mirage Palace's methods to test again.
I know you don't want others
to know about your sister's story.
That's why we are asking
about this in private.
Don't you want to know
if your sister has another daughter?
Okay. Let me sleep on it.
Do not reveal this
to anyone else.
Okay.
Su Ningzhen did agree to a blood test.
That means something strange
did happen when Su Ningxi was in labor.
That's why she's also suspicious.
We will know tomorrow.
Don't worry about it.
Worry?
I grew up with no parents by my side.
I'm used to being alone.
I've never thought of finding my family.
It's just that having
a relationship with Gao Qiumin
upsets me.
The result better shows that
there's no connection between us.
In that case, I won't need to hesitate
when I kill Gao Qiumin.
If you don't care about families
and have no expectations
about your parents,
why did you give up your task
and come to Mirage Palace,
which is most hostile to the Spirit Clan?
Because you will protect me.
-How stubborn.
-What do you care?
Related.
How are they related?
Why?
Master.
What are you looking for?
Let me help you.
DARK ABYSS
Is it possible that she's…
When we were in Snow City,
Mu Xuanling mentioned
that she was a spirit slave
in Moonlight Heights, right?
She also mentioned that Gao Fengxu
tried to kill her before he died,
right?
People say
that she's a Spirit Clan member,
yet no one has seen her original form.
She said that
her spiritual apertures were damaged.
She has no spiritual essence,
so she can't show her original form.
So, how do you know for sure
that she's a Spirit Clan member?
When she was young,
she had demon patterns on her face.
Golden imprints,
like runes.
That cannot be seen on human faces.
What kind of demon pattern?
Draw it.
Draw it and let me see.
I see.
This is
the truth about the light.
We were wrong.
All of us were wrong.
Master. What's going on with you?
Master.
I'm in bed.
I'm getting in after five seconds.
I'm telling you that I'm in bed.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
-What is it?
-We are in Mirage Palace.
I'm worried that you will stir things up.
So?
So, I'm going to keep you in check.
WARBLE HALL
Your mind is not clear right now.
I think it's better for me to watch you.
I was just staying in my room.
You barged in in the middle of the night.
Which one of us
is confused right now?
You, of course.
Is that you being reasonable?
I've tried to be reasonable.
-Did that work?
-Of course!
When you reasoned with me,
I felt like my mind was cleansed,
and I wanted to be
a good person deep down.
What's the most important thing
about being a good person?
Do not lie.
Fine.
Maybe I'm not that eager
to be a good person.
How about you?
You insisted
on hanging out in my room
at such a late hour.
That's not up to a gentleman's code.
I am no gentleman.
I can be ruthless.
If you don't want me to knock you out,
stay put.
Xie Xuechen.
You know that I'm not a good person.
Why do you have to fancy me?
I don't want to tell you right now.
If you want to know,
stay by my side.
Don't leave.
What if
I do a horrible thing one day?
Will you still fancy me?
Yes.
But I will be watching you,
so that you won't have
a chance to do that.
This man lives like a monk,
but his sweet words are so determined.
How strange!
We will know a few facts tomorrow.
About the Chaos Pearl, Su Ningxi,
and your identity.
Tonight,
stay and behave.
REJUVENATION PAVILION
What did Master mean today?
I was supposed to investigate
the Chaos Pearl.
How come I just keep
getting more mysteries?
I wonder if it's a good thing
if the whole truth comes out.
Miss Gao.
What brought you here?
I thought you were going
to wait outside the palace.
Are you here to make fun of me?
No, of course.
I got you some snacks.
I don't want you
to feel sad over what happened lately.
Even if I want to feel sad,
I don't even know where to get started.
There are so many things
that I want to know about my mother.
Did she love Sang Qi?
Or did she love my father?
If she gave up love
and married into Moonlight Heights,
has she ever been happy?
Did she look forward to my birth?
My father used to tell me
that he loved my mother deeply.
It's just that my mother
was taken away too soon
when giving birth to me.
Judging from what we know,
that might be nothing but a lie.